If I check this box in the app then it'll add the whipped cream
앱의 박스를 체크할 경우 커피의 토핑으로
topping to our coffee.
휘핑 크림이 더해집니다.
&gt;&gt; That will make the coffee more delicious.
&gt;&gt; 이는 커피를 더욱 맛있게 만들겠군요.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. &gt;&gt; And perhaps more expensive.
&gt;&gt; 예. &gt;&gt; 그리고 아마 더 비싸 지겠군요.
&gt;&gt; True.
&gt;&gt; 맞습니다.
Eventually we're going to have to learn how to create an order summary and
마침내 어떻게 주문을 하는지를 그리고 이를 어떻게 보내는지를
then send it off.
배워보았습니다
&gt;&gt; Oh, so when we send the order summary, that's when we get the coffee.
&gt;&gt; 오 이제 커피를 마시고 싶을 때 주문을 할 수 있겠군요
Right? &gt;&gt; Yeah.
그렇죠? &gt;&gt; 예.
&gt;&gt; That's good.
&gt;&gt; 좋습니다.
&gt;&gt; The problem is we don't exactly know if the box is checked or
&gt;&gt; 문제는 박스가 체크되었는지 아닌지를 정확히 모른다는
not &gt;&gt; Wait, you just checked the box.
것입니다. &gt;&gt; 잠시만요, 방금 박스를 체크하였습니다.
I know you checked the box.
박스를 체크하였다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
&gt;&gt; Well it's easy for a human to see, but it's hard for the phone to see.
&gt;&gt; 사람들은 이를 확인할 수 있지만, 전화로는 이를 확인하기가 힘듭니다.
&gt;&gt; Who you calling a human?
&gt;&gt; 누가 전화를 하나요?
&gt;&gt; Anyways, when you add the CheckBox to your app,
&gt;&gt; 어쨌든, 앱에 [CheckBox]를 추가하면,
then it's actually creating a Java object.
실질적으로 자바 객체를 만들게 됩니다.
[SOUND] Like this.
[소리] 이와 같이 말이죠.
&gt;&gt; How many of these boxes are out there?
&gt;&gt; 이러한 박스가 몇 개나 됩니까?
&gt;&gt; Many, because in fact, inside the CheckBox object we have a variable.
&gt;&gt; 많습니다. 사실, [CheckBox] 객체 안에는 변수가 있습니다.
&gt;&gt; Okay.
&gt;&gt; 좋습니다.
&gt;&gt; A Boolean variable.
&gt;&gt; 불 연산자 변수.
&gt;&gt; Boolean?
&gt;&gt; 불 연산자?
Haven't heard that word before.
들어본 적이 없습니다.
&gt;&gt; Well a Boolean just means that there's two states here.
&gt;&gt; 불 연산자는 이곳에 두 개의 상태가 있음을 의미합니다.
&gt;&gt; Like New York and California?
&gt;&gt; 뉴욕과 캘리포니아 처럼요?
&gt;&gt; No. It's more like a light switch.
&gt;&gt; 아니오. 전등 스위치와 같은 것입니다.
[SOUND] &gt;&gt; Damn it.
[소리] &gt;&gt; 이런.
How do you do this?
어떻게 해야 하나요?
Anyways.
어쨌든.
So you're saying when we created a CheckBox, we had a Java object.
체크박스를 만들면, 자바 객체를 갖게 되도록 하였습니다.
Inside of that we have a variable of type Boolean.
내부에 불 연산자와 같은 유형의 변수를 갖게 됩니다.
&gt;&gt; Right.
&gt;&gt; 맞습니다.
&gt;&gt; And the type of that variable is either on or off.
&gt;&gt; 이러한 변수의 유형은 켬 혹은 끔과 같은 것입니다.
&gt;&gt; The value of it is yeah, on or off.
&gt;&gt; 이것의 값, 예, 켬과 끔.
&gt;&gt; Okay, so I can turn the value from on to off.
&gt;&gt; 좋습니다. 따라서 값을 켬에서 끔으로 바꿀 수 있습니다.
&gt;&gt; I can't see anything.
&gt;&gt; 아무 것도 볼 수가 없어요.
Can you turn it back on?
다시 켜주시겠어요?
We're not done yet.
아직 하지 않았습니다.
&gt;&gt; Oh, okay. &gt;&gt; Okay, so
&gt;&gt; 아, 좋습니다. &gt;&gt; 자 그러면
Boolean can have two states, true or false.
불 연산자는 두 개의 상태를 갖습니다. O 또는 X.
And that represents the checked state of this CheckBox.
그리고 이는 체크 박스의 체크된 상태를 나타냅니다.
&gt;&gt; Whoa, that's a lot of checks in that statement.
&gt;&gt; 와우, 여기에는 다양한 체크의 종류들이 있군요.
Let's just back up.
이를 저장해 봅시다.
I'm going to summarize.
이를 요약할 것입니다.
Tell me if I got this wrong.
잘못된 점이 있으면 말해주세요.
So when we create the CheckBox we created this Java object.
체크박스를 만들게 되면, 자바 객체를 만들게 됩니다.
Inside of that Java object we have a variable.
자바 객체 내부에는 변수가 있습니다.
Its type happens to be Boolean, and that type of variable can hold two values,
불 연산자와 같이 나타나는 유형이고 이러한 변수의 유형은 켬이나 끔, 하나
either on or off, one or zero, true or false.
혹은 0, O 또는 X의 두 개의 값을 가질 수 있습니다.
&gt;&gt; Exactly.
&gt;&gt; 정확합니다.
&gt;&gt; Okay. So let's play with the Boolean.
&gt;&gt; 좋습니다. 불 연산자를 통해 확인해 보도록 합시다.
[SOUND] &gt;&gt; Okay.
[소리] &gt;&gt; 좋습니다.
it's time to take that away from you.
이제 끝낼 시간입니다.
[LAUGH] Let's look at what the documentation
[웃음] 불 연산자에 관한 문서의 내용을
says about Booleans.
살펴보도록 합시다
I'm going to Google search for Java data type.
자바 데이터 유형에 관해 구글 검색을 해 보겠습니다.
That's because Boolean is one of the primitive data types in Java.
왜냐하면 불 연산자는 자바의 주요 데이터 유형 중의 하나이기 때문입니다.
Primitive, meaning basic data types.
기본적 데이터 유형을 의미하는 프리미티브.
I'm going to scroll through this list of primitive
이 프리미티브 데이터 유형의 목록을 불 연산자가 나올 때까지 스크롤을
data types until I find Boolean.
움직여 보도록 하겠습니다.
And here it is.
여기 있네요.
It says the Boolean data type only has two possible values, true and false.
불 연산자 데이터 유형은 O 또는 X 두 개의 값만을 가진다고 나와있네요.
It's used for simple flags that track true and false conditions.
O 또는 X 조건을 조회하는 간단한 플래그에 사용됩니다.
Then it says that a Boolean takes up one bit of information.
그리고 불 연산자는 1비트의 정보만 갖는다고 나왔네요.
This is about how much space it takes up on a computer.
이는 컴퓨터에서 얼마나 많은 공간을 차지하느냐를 뜻하는 것입니다.
Anyways, the important part is that a Boolean has two possible values.
어쨌든, 중요한 것은 불 연산자가 두 개의 값을 갖는다는 것입니다.
You might think that true and
이들은 문자이기 때문에 O 또는 X가
false are actually string values because they're text, but
실질적으로 문자열 값이라고 생각해 볼 수 있습니다. 하지만 실질적으로
actually, they're not in double quotations, so they're not strings.
이들은 큰 따옴표 안에 있는 내용이 아니기 때문에 문자열이 아닙니다.
They're actually fixed literal values.
이들은 실질적으로 고정된 문자 값입니다.
Do you remember how fixed literal values are zero and one or
어떻게 고정된 문자 값이 0과 1 혹은 안녕이나 오늘과 같은 특정 문자열이
specific strings like hello or today?
되는지 기억하십니까?
That means that when you create a Boolean variable you can set it to one
이는 불 연산자 변수를 만들 때, 이 두 값 중의 하나로 설정할 수 있음을
of these two values.
의미합니다.
Going back to our box analogy, if we have a variable called isChecked and
박스 비유부분으로 돌아가 봅시다. [isChecked]라는 변수를 가지고
it stores information on whether a CheckBox is checked or not,
체크박스에 체크가 되었는지에 관한 정보를 저장할 경우 이 불 연산자
then inside this Boolean variable we can store the value true.
변수에는 O라는 값을 저장할 수 있습니다.
Then we can interpret this as the CheckBox being checked.
그리고 이를 체크박스에 체크되었다고 설명할 수 있습니다.
Or we can store the value false inside this variable.
아니면 이 변수 안에 X라는 값을 저장할 수 있습니다.
Then we could interpret this as the CheckBox not being checked.
그리고 이를 체크박스가 체크되지 않았다고 설명할 수 있습니다.
A Boolean is great for having two possible states.
불 연산자는 두 가지 가능한 상태를 가질 수 있기 때문에 대단합니다.
Then it's up to you as a developer to interpret what true and false maps to.
그리고 O 또는 X로 설명될 지의 여부는 개발자인 당신에게 달렸습니다.
If you need more than two possible states then you can't use a Boolean.
두 개 이상의 상태가 필요할 경우 불 연산자를 사용할 수 없습니다.
You need to use something else like a string or an integer.
문자열이나 정수와 같은 다른 것을 사용하여야 합니다.
Declaring a Boolean variable is very similar to declaring an int.
불 연산자 변수의 규정은 [int]의 규정과 매우 유사합니다.
It's not as complicated as creating an object variable.
객체 변수를 만드는 것 만큼 복잡하지 않습니다.
It follows the format of Boolean hasWhippedCream = true.
hasWhippedCream = true인 불 연산자의 형식을 따릅니다.
We have the data type, which is Boolean, followed by the variable name, which
변수 명에 따라 우리가 원하는 무엇이든지 될 수 있는 그리고 초기
can be anything we want, and then the initial value which is true or false.
값은 O 또는 X인 불 연산자 데이터 유형을 가지고 있습니다.
Here are a couple of other examples.
여기에 몇몇 다른 예시가 있습니다.
This is where I set the same Boolean to be false.
여기에서는 같은 불 연산자를 X로 설정해 보겠습니다.
And here's a different Boolean called isRegistered,
그리고 이곳에 [isRegistered]인 다른 불 연산자가 있습니다.
and I just initialize that to false.
이를 X로 초기화 해보겠습니다.
For example, this variable could represent whether a user using our app
예를 들어, 이 변수는 사용자가 우리에 의해 등록된
actually has a registered account with us.
앱을 사용하는지를 나타낼 수 있습니다.
Here's another example.
여기 다른 예시가 있습니다.
Boolean isOrderForPickup = true.
Boolean isOrderForPickup = true.
This variable could represent whether someone putting in an order for
이 변수는 누군가가 커피를 가게에서 마실 것인지 혹은 테이크 아웃 할
some coffee wants to pick it up at the store or have it delivered.
것인지에 관해 주문하는 것을 나타낼 수 있습니다.
While our app doesn't support these features, you can imagine how using
우리 앱은 이러한 기능을 지원하지 못하지만 두 가지 상태를 가지고 있으므로
Booleans could be useful because these things have two possible states.
어떻게 불 연산자를 유용하게 이용할 것인지를 생각해 볼 수 있습니다.
Also notice the way I named these variables.
이러한 변수들을 명명하는 방법을 잘 알아두십시오.
A Boolean variable name has to follow the same conventions as other
불 연산자 변수 명은 다른 변수 명과 같은 규정을
variable names.
따라야 합니다.
However, it's common to start with something like has something or
하지만, 무엇을 가진 것과 같은 혹은 무엇으로 시작하는 것이
is something.
일반적입니다.
When you see names with has or is, it's likely a Boolean but not always.
~를 갖거나 ~인 명칭을 살펴보면, 대부분 불 연산자인 경우가 많습니다.
What I'm about to show you is a little more advanced and optional.
더욱 진화되고 선택적인 내용을 보여드리도록 하겠습니다.
So if you're interested you can follow along.
관심이 있으시다면, 따라오시기 바랍니다.
This is the documentation page for the CheckBox class.
이것은 체크박스 클래스에 대한 문서 페이지입니다.
I'm going to click on view source to look at the source code for
체크박스 클래스와 같은 소스 코드를 살펴보기 위해 뷰 소스를 클릭해
the CheckBox class.
보도록 하겠습니다.
This code is saved in the CheckBox.java file.
코드는 CheckBox.java file에 저장되었습니다.
I want to show you that there's a Boolean variable inside of this
이 체크박스 클래스 내에 불 연산자 변수가 있다는 것을 보여드리고자
CheckBox class.
합니다.
But I don't see it here, so let's check the super class.
하지만 여기서는 보여드리지는 않을 것이므로 슈퍼 클래스를 확인해 봅시다.
If this value is true then the CheckBox is checked.
이 값이 O이면 체크박스가 체크됩니다.
If it's false then the box is not checked.
X이면 박스가 체크되지 않습니다.
You'll notice that this name doesn't contain the word has or is, but
이 명칭은 가지다 나 이다 라는 단어를 포함하지 않음을 알게 될 것입니다.
if you go down here you'll see that the other Boolean variables
하지만 아래를 살펴보면 가지다 라는 단어를 포함한 다른 불 연산자 변수를
do have the word has in it.
확인하게 될 것입니다.
It's all a matter of preference for the developer.
이는 모두 개발자의 참조와 관련된 사항입니다.
In this case, it's probably pretty clear that this is a Boolean for
이 같은 경우에, 이것이 체크 상태에 대한 불 연산자임이 더욱 명확해 질
the checked state.
것입니다.
And while this Boolean is not found directly in the CheckBox.java file,
이 불 연산자는 CheckBox.javafile에서 직접적으로 확인되지 않습니다.
since we're inheriting from the CompoundButton class,
[CompoundButton] 클래스로부터 이 불 연산자를 받았기 때문에 이 체크된
we get this checked Boolean for free.
불 연산자를 자유롭게 사용할 수 있습니다.
In general, looking at the source code for
일반적으로, 안드로이드 클래스에서
the Android classes isn't required at all.
소스 코드를 찾는 것을 더 이상은 요구하지 않습니다.
To develop Android apps,
안드로이드 앱 개발을 위해,
all you need to know is how to look at the documentation pages.
알아야 할 것은 어떻게 문서 페이지를 살펴보는지 입니다.
Okay, so in this video we learned about how Booleans can store
좋습니다. 이 영상에서, 어떻게 불 연산자가 O 또는 X의 값을
a value of true or false.
저장하는지를 배웠습니다.
In this quiz, practice creating a Boolean variable and
이 퀴즈에서, 불 연산자 변수를 만드는 것을 연습하고 제공된 박스에 있는
updating it by typing out the lines of code in the boxes provided.
코드 행에 입력하여 업데이트 해 보도록 하십시오.
Type this line exactly in here and same for the other boxes.
이 행을 이곳과 다른 박스에 똑같이 정확히 입력하십시오
Then I want you to think about other good use cases for
그리고 불 연산자에 정보를 저장하는 다른 유용한 활용 사례를 생각해
storing information in a Boolean.
보기를 바랍니다.
Think about what has two possible states.
어떤 것이 두 가지 상태를 가질 수 있는지를 생각해 보십시오.
Do you ever use alarm clock on your phone to wake up?
기상을 위해 핸드폰에 있는 알람 시계를 사용해 본 적이 있습니까?
Well chances are that when you turn your alarm on or
여기에서 알람을 켜거나 끄는 것은
off, that that's actually getting stored as a Boolean variable.
실질적으로 불 연산자 변수로 저장되었습니다.
Another possible Boolean variable is whether you want to
다른 가능한 불 연산자 변수는 알람의 반복을 원하느냐
repeat an alarm or not.
아니냐 입니다.
In the Gmail app, if I really want to star this special message that I got
Gmail 앱에서, 제가 하고자 하는 것은 2011년 Gmail 팀으로부터 받은 특별
from the Gmail team in 2011, then I can star it, or I can unstar it.
메시지에 별표를 하는 것입니다. 저는 별표를 하거나 하지 않을 수 있습니다.
Since this has two states, it could be stored as a Boolean variable.
여기에 두 가지 상태가 있기 때문에, 불 연산자 변수로 저장될 수 있습니다.
A possible Boolean variable name for that could be isStarred.
이에 대한 가능한 불 연산자 변수 명은 [isStarred]일 것입니다.
You could also use a Boolean variable to keep track of whether an email
또한 이메일이 읽혔는지를 조회하기 위해 불 연산자 변수를 사용할 수
is read or not.
있습니다.
This email is unread, whereas this email is already read.
이 이메일은 읽히지 않았지만 이 이메일은 이미 읽혔습니다.
Speaking of YouTube let's go to the YouTube app.
유투브에 관한 말하기, 유투브 앱을 살펴보도록 합시다.
In the YouTube app, when it displays a list of videos,
유투브 앱에서, 최근 영상이 등록되었을 때
if I've already watched it, then it shows this little text box here
이미 보았을 경우, 섬네일 이미지의 왼쪽 윗부분에서
that says watched in the top left corner of the thumbnail image.
확인하였다는 작은 문자 상자를 이곳에 보여줍니다.
The fact that I've watched or
내가 영상을 보았는지 안 보았는지는
not watched the video could also be stored as a Boolean variable.
또한 불 연산자 변수로 저장될 수 있습니다.
I just showed you some use cases for Booleans, so
불 연산자에 대한 활용 사례를 보여드렸습니다. 따라서 여러분 만의
try to come up with your own here.
내용을 이곳에 보여주십시오.
You can browse existing Android apps for some ideas.
아이디어를 위해 기존의 안드로이드 앱을 살펴보시면 됩니다.